Contact

yodixon2000@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/yolondadixon-81789159 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

BLS

Nursing

ACLS

Languages

English

French

Honors-Awards

Daisy Award Recipient Humankindness Award

Yolonda Dixon

Travel Nurse at Travel Nurse Across America Longview

Summary

I am self motivated. I enjoy helping people as well as educating them on their care. God and family first. One of my objectives is to increase my knowledge and experience at the same time using my present knowledge and experience assisting in co-working in different areas/facilities.

Experience

Travel Nurse Across America
Travel Nurse
October 2014 - Present (5 years 11 months)

Current Nursing license. I travel locally or nationally to work on short-term assignments to help supplement current nursing staff at hospitals and clinics. Responsibilities include treating patients, and providing advice and emotional support to patients' family members. Treating patients includes recording medical histories and symptoms, performing diagnostic tests, and administering medications. I work on IMC - Stroke/Neurological and Cardiovascular, Post Surgical, PCU, NPCU, Neuro/Tele, Bipap units and working to get back in the Postpartum field as well. Travel history has been Houston, Tx(3mos); Lewisgale Salem VA(3mos), Methodist Hospital San Antonio Tx(9mos), Chandler Regional Chandler AZ(11mos 24days) and presently at Rust Presbyterian Rio Rancho New Mexico.

Good Shepherd Health System Registered Nurse August 2013 - August 2015 (2 years 1 month) Longview, Texas Area

Stroke and Cardiovascular IMC unit. Admit and discharge patients, start IV's and IV care. Administer medication, monitor lab values, bedside care, some respiratory care, some end of life care, Picc line care, NIH and MEND assessments, chart reviews and making sure MD orders were followed.

Trinity Mother Frances Health System Registered Nurse

Page 1 of 3

February 2010 - August 2013 (3 years 7 months)

Though we do not have PALS certification we have NPR certification. From 12/2009 to 9/2010 I was on 5Dawson the neuroscience unit. I also served in it's EMU unit monitoring our seizure patients or those with potential seizures. Admited patients, started IV's and IV care. Administered medication, monitored lab values, Bedside care, some Respiratory care, some end of life care, Picc line care, NIH and MEND assessments, chart reviews and making sure MD orders were followed. I have been on Mother Baby/Postpartum unit since 9/2011. Perform care for postpartum mothers and their newborns. Teaching done on postpartum care, signs and symptoms of hemorrhaging/clots and other complications, Infant care and complications, and Breastfeeding. Do admissions as well as prepare both mother and baby for discharge. We also provided care for women who having complication but are not ready for delivery (antepartum) as well as women who are in and have had gyneclogical surgeries and require postoperation care.

Trinity Clinic- Trinity Mother Frances
Lead LVN
February 2000 - December 2009 (9 years 11 months)

I was lead nurse for TC- kilgore, I did the following; teaching patients, took care of the kilgore college students and faculty, scheduled appointments, scheduled procedures, lab call backs, patient call backs, insurance prior authorizations, prescription refills per protocol, nurse and chart audits, supply ordering, filled in as switchboard as needed, filled in at lab as needed, filled in as floor nurse as needed, maintained paperwork as necessary for doctors, gave injections for the clinical assistants as needed, did medical records as needed, monitored and sorted the mail as needed as well as monitored and sorted fax correspondances.

Highland Pines Retirement Center part time LVN floor nurse
June 2007 - January 2008 (8 months)

Care of nursing home patients ranging form 10-26 in number. Ranged from skin care, ostomy care, feeding tubes, iv therapy, medication administration, safety issues as well as rehab addressed.

The Willows Retirement Center wound care nurse - LVN June 2005 - December 2005 (7 months) kilgore texas

part time work as wound care nurse on the weekends, skin assessments of newly admitted patients, and assisted regular staff as needed when my cycle of skin care was completed.

Education

Kilgore College

Associate's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2007 - 2009)

Southern Arkansas University

Bachelor's degree, Psychology · (1985 - 1989)